{
    "notes": "Sebutkan bentuk verb 1,2,3 dari kata kerja tak beraturan di bawah ini",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "timbul, muncul atau bangun",
            "answer": "arise, arose, arisen",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "terbangun, bangun",
            "answer": "awake, awoke, awoken",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menjadi",
            "answer": "be, was/were, been",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "melahirkan, membawa",
            "answer": "bear, bore, borne/born",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengalahkan",
            "answer": "beat, beat, beaten",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mulai",
            "answer": "begin, began, begun",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membungkuk",
            "answer": "bend, bent, bent",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "bertaruh",
            "answer": "bet, bet, bet",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengikat",
            "answer": "bind, bound, bound",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menggigit",
            "answer": "bite, bit, bitten",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berdarah",
            "answer": "bleed, bled, bled",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "tiup",
            "answer": "blow, blew, blown",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "pecah",
            "answer": "break, broke, broken",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membawa",
            "answer": "bring, brought, brought",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membangun",
            "answer": "build, built, built",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membeli",
            "answer": "buy, bought, bought",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menangkap",
            "answer": "catch, caught, caught",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memilih",
            "answer": "choose, chose, chosen",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "datang",
            "answer": "come, came, come",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "biaya",
            "answer": "cost, cost, cost",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memotong",
            "answer": "cut, cut, cut",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berurusan, menangani",
            "answer": "deal, dealt, dealt",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menggali",
            "answer": "dig, dug, dug",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "melakukan",
            "answer": "do, did, done",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menggambar",
            "answer": "draw, drew, drawn",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "minum",
            "answer": "drink, drank, drunk",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengemudi",
            "answer": "drive, drove, driven",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "makan",
            "answer": "eat, ate, eaten",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "jatuh",
            "answer": "fall, fell, fallen",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memberi makan",
            "answer": "feed, fed, fed",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "merasa",
            "answer": "feel, felt, felt",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "bertarung",
            "answer": "fight, fought, fought",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menemukan",
            "answer": "find, found, found",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "terbang",
            "answer": "fly, flew, flown",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "melupakan",
            "answer": "forget, forgot, forgotten",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memaafkan",
            "answer": "forgive, forgave, forgiven",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membeku",
            "answer": "freeze, froze, frozen",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mendapatkan",
            "answer": "get, got, gotten/got",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memberikan",
            "answer": "give, gave, given",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "pergi",
            "answer": "go, went, gone",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "tumbuh",
            "answer": "grow, grew, grown",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memiliki",
            "answer": "have, had, had",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mendengar",
            "answer": "hear, heard, heard",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menyembunyikan",
            "answer": "hide, hid, hidden",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memukul",
            "answer": "hit, hit, hit",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menahan",
            "answer": "hold, held, held",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "melukai",
            "answer": "hurt, hurt, hurt",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menjaga",
            "answer": "keep, kept, kept",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "tahu",
            "answer": "know, knew, known",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "meletakkan",
            "answer": "lay, laid, laid",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memimpin",
            "answer": "lead, led, led",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "meninggalkan",
            "answer": "leave, left, left",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "meminjamkan",
            "answer": "lend, lent, lent",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membiarkan",
            "answer": "let, let, let",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berbaring",
            "answer": "lie, lay, lain",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menyalakan",
            "answer": "light, lit, lit",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "kehilangan",
            "answer": "lose, lost, lost",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membuat",
            "answer": "make, made, made",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berarti",
            "answer": "mean, meant, meant",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "bertemu",
            "answer": "meet, met, met",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membayar",
            "answer": "pay, paid, paid",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "meletakkan",
            "answer": "put, put, put",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membaca",
            "answer": "read, read, read",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengendarai",
            "answer": "ride, rode, ridden",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berdering",
            "answer": "ring, rang, rung",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "naik",
            "answer": "rise, rose, risen",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "lari",
            "answer": "run, ran, run",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengatakan",
            "answer": "say, said, said",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "melihat",
            "answer": "see, saw, seen",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mencari",
            "answer": "seek, sought, sought",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menjual",
            "answer": "sell, sold, sold",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengirim",
            "answer": "send, sent, sent",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menetapkan",
            "answer": "set, set, set",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengguncang",
            "answer": "shake, shook, shaken",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "bersinar",
            "answer": "shine, shone, shone",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menembak",
            "answer": "shoot, shot, shot",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menunjukkan",
            "answer": "show, showed, shown",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengecil",
            "answer": "shrink, shrank/shrunk, shrunk",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menutup",
            "answer": "shut, shut, shut",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menyanyi",
            "answer": "sing, sang, sung",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "tenggelam",
            "answer": "sink, sank, sunk",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "duduk",
            "answer": "sit, sat, sat",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "tidur",
            "answer": "sleep, slept, slept",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "meluncur",
            "answer": "slide, slid, slid",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berbicara",
            "answer": "speak, spoke, spoken",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menghabiskan",
            "answer": "spend, spent, spent",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berputar",
            "answer": "spin, spun, spun",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "membelah",
            "answer": "split, split, split",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menyebar",
            "answer": "spread, spread, spread",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berdiri",
            "answer": "stand, stood, stood",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mencuri",
            "answer": "steal, stole, stolen",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menancapkan",
            "answer": "stick, stuck, stuck",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menusuk",
            "answer": "sting, stung, stung",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memukul",
            "answer": "strike, struck, struck/stricken",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "bersumpah",
            "answer": "swear, swore, sworn",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menyapu",
            "answer": "sweep, swept, swept",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berenang",
            "answer": "swim, swam, swum",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengayun",
            "answer": "swing, swung, swung",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengambil",
            "answer": "take, took, taken",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "mengajar",
            "answer": "teach, taught, taught",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "merobek",
            "answer": "tear, tore, torn",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menceritakan",
            "answer": "tell, told, told",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "berpikir",
            "answer": "think, thought, thought",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "melempar",
            "answer": "throw, threw, thrown",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memahami",
            "answer": "understand, understood, understood",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "bangun",
            "answer": "wake, woke, woken",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "memakai",
            "answer": "wear, wore, worn",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menang",
            "answer": "win, won, won",
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "question": "menulis",
            "answer": "write, wrote, written",
            "explanation": ""
        }
    ]
}
